# Sergio H. Junqueira dos Santos

Email: sergiojunqueira.s@gmail.comAddress: Imbituba, SC - BrazilLinkedin: Sergio Junqueira | LinkedInPhone: +55 (48) 98809-2925

My stack includes proficiency in Python and SQL for data, as well as advanced data engineering tools like Apache Spark, Databricks, and dbt. I am experienced in building and managing data pipelines, working with both structured and unstructured data, and utilizing cloud platforms such as Google Cloud. I also have strong skills in data visualization with Looker and Power BI.

Currently, I am focusing on transitioning into Full Stack Development, enhancing my skills in technologies such as React, Next.js, Node.js, and GraphQL. I am actively pursuing a broader technical skill set to become a more versatile and well-rounded professional, combining my data engineering background with modern web development.

Github: <a href="https://github.com/sjunqueira">https://github.com/sjunqueira</a>

### Education

#### **Computer Engineer**

Universidade Cruzeiro do Sul

Aug, 24 - Jul, 29 (On course)

## **Experience**

#### Tech Lead (Interim) Data & BI Team

Grupo Boticário

Curitiba, PR, Brazil - Nov, 2024 - Present

- Leading the Data & BI team, implementing scalable, high-performance solutions.
- Defining data architecture to integrate different sources and optimize analysis processes.
- Developing dashboards and strategic reports for executive and operation decision-making.
- Collaborating with IT and Engineering teams to ensure alignment between technical and business requirements.

#### **Analytics Engineer**

PagoNxt Merchant Solutions,

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil - Apr, 2024 - Nov, 2024

- Coordinated activities of Analytics Engineer while concurrently managing responsibilities of Data Analyst for a period of time.
- Created an MVP for data quality of one of the company's main products.

#### **Senior Data Analyst**

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil - oct, 2023 - Jun, 2024

- Develop dashboards and automate processes for new products, collaborating with business areas.
- Utilize SQL, Python, Scala, Databricks, and Power Bl.
- Led the creation of a dashboard aimed at optimizing marketing campaigns for a \$60M+ product, taking on responsibilities for query development, job automation, dataset development and maintenance, and comprehensive project documentation.

#### **Data Analyst**

Alura,

São Paulo, SP, Brazil - oct, 2021 - oct, 2023

- Principal data person in the commercial team, focused on educating the team and conducting engagement studies for major clients.
- Utilized Power BI, SQL, Python for automation, and Excel to provide data to non-technical users.
- Led the reformulation of governance processes and results presentation for the largest client, resulting in a multi-year contract. Conducted an ROI study that prevented churn and generated a 20% upsell.
- Educated non-technical team through data-related presentations.

#### Partner & Data Lead

Torceai,

Maringá, PR, Brazil - jan, 2021 - jan, 2023

- Enhanced the database by migrating from a Star Schema model to Snowflake, using MySQL Workbench and Apache Airflow.
- Designed and implemented Management Information Dashboards to monitor key metrics such as client totals, revenue, and internal processes.

#### Partner e Full Stack Developer

Torceai,

Maringá, PR, Brazil - aug, 2019 - jan, 2021

 Contributed to the development and maintenance of the company's product using Node.js and Angular.

#### **Junior Data Analyst**

Anymarket,

Maringá, PR, Brazil - jul, 2020 - jun, 2021

- Analyzed data and provided reports to managers and teams, primarily using Excel and basic SQL.
- Led the implementation of the Customer Success software, defining churn metrics and scores.
- Created a CRM-integrated table that eliminated internal gueries about client managers.

#### **Customer Success / Key Account**

#### aiqfome,

Maringá, PR, Brazil - fev 2019 - jun, 2020

- · Managed brand licensees, setting and tracking monthly targets.
- Analyzed results and identified issues to plan and implement effective solutions in commercial, marketing, financial, and legislative areas.
- Was responsible, alongside the Head of Farming, for the internal account clustering structure.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Frontend Development: React, Next.js, Angular, JavaScript (ES6+), HTML, CSS
- Backend Development: Node.js, Express, NestJS, GraphQL, TypeORM, Prisma
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL
- Data Engineering: SQL, Apache Spark, Snowflake, dbt, Databricks, Airflow, Power BI, Tableau
- DevOps & Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Git, Jest
- Cloud & Storage: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), S3